Yale School of Music Graduate Degree Projects
Yale University Music Library
Graduate degree projects
1961-1971
Misc. Ms. 51
Yale University Music Library
2.5
(6 boxes)
This collection contains the final written projects of 63 students who were candidates for the Master of Music or Master of Musical Arts degree in the Yale School of Music from 1961 to 1971.
Yale School of Music
Conditions Governing Access
Degree projects are made available for research in the Music Library upon application to a Music Library staff member. Please contact Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. In some instances, permission to access an individual project may also require permission from the author.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by author's name.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the final written projects of 63 students who were candidates for the Master of Music or Master of Musical Arts degree in the Yale School of Music from 1961 to 1971. These projects were not collected systematically, so some students who received such degrees during that period may not be represented.
Music -- Instruction and study -- United States; Yale School of Music
- A Survey of the Pipe Organs Designed by G. Donald Harrison, 1970; Alexander, Richard (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Organ Sonata from C.P.E. Bach to Max Reger, 1969; Anderson, Marion Reddick (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Some Aspects of Baroque Performance Practice on the Organ, 1969; Anderson, Marion Reddick (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Szymanowski's Mazurkas - Analysis and Comparison to Chopin's Mazurkas, 1969; Apter, David (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A Study of Some Important Passages from the First Movement Cello Part to the Beethoven A Major Sonata for Pianoforte and Cello, 1969; Austin, David (Box 1, Folder 5)
- A Tape of 34 "Takes" from Some Important Passages from the First Movement Cello Part to the Beethoven A Major Sonata for Pianoforte and Cello, 1970; Austin, David (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cadenzas for Three Mozart Works, 1969; Aylward, Ansgarius (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  1. Violin Concerto in A Major
  2. Violin Concerto in G Major
  3. Symphonie Concertante in E-flat Major for Violin and Viola
- Teaching Voice Classes in Secondary Schools, 1968; Baldwin, Ronald (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Sonata in f minor, Opus 120, No. 1 by Johannes Brahms: A Musical Analysis and Interpretive Study, 1969; Boito, Charles P. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Byzantine Liturgy of the Pre-sanctified Gifts: Communion Hymns in Fourteenth and Fifteenth Century Akolouthiai Manuscripts, 1969; Breslich, Helen Louise (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Remarques sur L'Art de Bien Chanter de Benigne de Bacilly, 1668, 1969; Christie, William Lincoln (Box 1, Folder 10)
- An Introduction to the Right Hand Technique of the Violoncello, 1969; Church, Frank V. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  (movie tape included)
- Brahms' Piano Technique, Piano Works, and the Fifty-one Exercises for Piano, 1969; Colburn, Carol D. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Chopin's Piano Technique and the Etudes Op. 10 and 25, 1969; Colburn, Carol D. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A Study of Performance Problems in the Second String Quartet (1907-1913) of Charles E. Ives (1874-1954), 1969; Cowan, Carole (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Music of the Roman Rite with a Discussion of Seven Masses, 1962; Curran, Louis (Box 2, Folder 4)
- A Sight-Reading Program for Trombone, 1969; Davies, Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Pieces for Harpsichord, 1970; De Silva, Preethi (Box 2, Folder 6)
  1. Prelude for the Left Hand
  2. Alamkara and Tala
- The French Symphonists: A Study of the Works of Widor and Vierne and Their Successors, 1969; Dilday, Susan (Box 3, Folder 1)
- The Piano Music of Francis Poulenc, 1969; Eberle, Bruce H. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- A Study in Early French Organ Music Through the Collections of Pierre Attaingnant and Jean Titelouze, 1970; Emery, Lynden (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The Cultural and Artistic Origins of Edgard Varèse, 1969; Enenbach, Fredric (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Towards a Description of the Listening Process in Language and Music, 1969; Fay, Thomas C. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Die Schweigsame Frau, The Collaboration of Richard Strauss and Stefan Zweig, 1971; Fuchs, Joseph, 1900-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Metronome Tape, 1969; Fujiki, Kunie (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Composition in Mixed Media, 1969; Fuller, Geoffrey T. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- The Horn Concerto - K. 495 in E Flat by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart with A Comparative Study of Contemporary and Historical Performance Practice, Gindin, Samuel Don (Box 3, Folder 9)
- An Analytical Index of Advanced Trumpet Methods in Terms of the Practical Benefits They Provide, 1969; Green, Richard F. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Brahms and the Clarinet: Trio Op. 114 for Pianoforte, Clarinet and Violoncello, 1969; Grice, Paul (Box 3, Folder 11)
- The Organ Music of Hugo Distler, 1969; Harbach, Barbara C. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- The Perception of Music as Composition, An Introduction to Properties of Form, 1969; Hope, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 1)
- The Development of the Piano Pedal Mechanism: Notation of Pedalling by Mozart, Haydn, and Beethoven, 1969; Howells, Eleanor (Box 4, Folder 2)
- An Introduction to Functional Vocal Training, 1969; Hui, Helen Kwok (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Vocal Music of the Ibo and Yoruba Tribes of West Africa, A Comparative Study, 1969; Ingram, Clinton (Box 4, Folder 4)
- A Survey of Organ Literature in the Sixteenth Century, 1969; Johnson, James E. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Expression and Stylistic Change, 1969; Johnston, Donald W. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Directions in Twentieth-Century Vocal Music, 1969; Johnston, Donald W. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Phrasing and Articulation in Baroque Music, 1969; Jonas, Linda (Box 4, Folder 8)
- The Art of Reed-Making for the Clarinet, 1969; Kramer, Steven (Box 4, Folder 9)
- The Influence of Gypsy Music on the Classical Violin Repertoire, 1969; Logan, Jane (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Louis Moreau Gottschalk: His Significance as the First American Pianist and Composer, 1969; Lounsbery, Lois (Box 4, Folder 11)
- A Study of King Arthur or the British Worthy, A Dramatic Opera The Words by John Dryden, The Music by Henry Purcell, 1969; Macklin, Paige Hatfield (Box 4, Folder 12)
- The Solo Clarinet Music of Georg Friedrich Fuchs and Franz Tausch, 1969; Mansfield, Peter Hall (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Partitas of Neo-Classic German Organ Composers, 1969; Marek, Patricia Ann (Box 4, Folder 14)
- The Beginnings of Handel's Oratorio in Italy: "La Resurezzione" and "Il Trionfo del Tempo a del Disinganno", More, Bruce E. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Guidelines for String Players to Develop Efficient Habits of Practicing, 1969; Moulyn, Charlotte A. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- A Comparative Study of Chopin and Scriabine, Including the Artistic and Political Influences on Both Composers, 1968; Nelson, Karen (Box 4, Folder 17)
- An Interpretive Study of the Recorded Chopin Preludes, 1969; Nelson, Karen (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Slide Technique for the Trombone: A Practical Method, 1969; Peck, Benjamin S. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- A Comparative Analysis of Five Organ Method Publications, 1961; Piehler, Wendell (Box 5, Folder 1)
- John Stanley (1713-1786) A Biography and Compendium of His Keyboard Works, 1970; Piehler, Wendell (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Supplement to John Stanley (1713-1786) A Biography and Compendium of His Keyboard Works, 1970; Piehler, Wendell (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Selected Performances of Three Works by Frédéric Chopin: An Analytical Comparison, 1969; Prizer, Margaret B. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Some Bolognese Sonate con Tromba: Edition and Commentary, Volume I, 1969; Prizer, William F. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Some Bolognese Sonate con Tromba, Edition and Commentary, Volume II, 1969; Prizer, William F. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The Relationship of Music to Ancient Chinese Culture, 1969; Ross, Barry (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Plans for an Opera called Death of a Gunfighter, 1968; Rylands, Mary Lou (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Brahms: The Seven Fantasies, Op. 116, A Study of Relationships within a Unified Structure, 1970; Schmalfeldt, Janet (Box 6, Folder 3)
- A Transcription of Four Bach Chorale Preludes for Oboe and Organ and Oboe and Strings, 1969; Seidel, W. Joseph (Box 6, Folder 4)
- The Flute and the Recorder as Described by Virdung, Agricola, Praetorius, and Mersenne, 1969; Shires, Jill (Box 6, Folder 5)
- A Survey of Purcell's Music for Trumpet, 1969; Simms, Bryan R. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- The Influence of Paganini, the Virtuoso, 1969; Soong, Lily (Box 6, Folder 7)
- An Analysis of Three Orgelbüchlein Chorale Preludes and a Comparison of Them with Settings of the Same Melody by Predecessors and Contemporaries of J.S. Bach, 1969; Staton, Ellen Lois (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Toward the Independence of Any Two Aspects of Violin-Playing, An Essay for Violinists, Stepner, Daniel (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Contemporary Techniques for the Clarinet, 1967; Stoltzman, Richard, 1942- (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Compositional and Stylistic Tends of American Contemporary Organ Music Looking Backward Over Fifty Years, Sunderland, Martin R. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- The Muting Techniques of the French Horn, 1969; Undercofler, James F. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Sonata XI for Viola, with Cello and Keyboard Accompaniment by Johann Schenck, 1969; Weidringer, Roselyn S. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- A Program of Study in Electronic Music, Wherein Equipment and Composition Techniques Pertinent to the Classic Electronic Music Studio will be Examined, 1969; Weinland, J. David (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Impressionism and Symbolism in the Proses Lyriques of Claude Debussy, 1967; White, Lois (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Index and Source for Study of the Orchestral Literature for Trumpet, 1969; Wich, Walter William (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Bach Cantata Arias for Tenor and Obligato Instruments, 1968; Williams, Ralph (Box 6, Folder 16)